Alaska
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Alaska, 2.1.3.2
  - Alaska: Vance photographs, 1929 - 1930; 5 (Box 1517)
    - V-19; An Eskimo woman, Shum-mik. Rather a fine old lady who lives at Baker Lake. She does excellent needle work and has seen many winters. She is of the tribe Hanermuit, 19
    - Verso: V-19; An Eskimo woman, Shum-mik. Rather a fine old lady who lives at Baker Lake. She does excellent needle work and has seen many winters. She is of the tribe Hanermuit, 19-verso
    - V-20; Kay ak took is of the tribe Aksiligsilingmuit, a member of one of the more primitive tribes. Many members of this tribe had never seen a trading post, usually sending one of two men into Baker Lake once a year to trade for the entire tribe, 20
    - Verso: V-20; Kay ak took is of the tribe Aksiligsilingmuit, a member of one of the more primitive tribes. Many members of this tribe had never seen a trading post, usually sending one of two men into Baker Lake once a year to trade for the entire tribe, 20-verso
    - V-21; A typical Eskimo kommitik[?] with the entire household goods packed up ready to move two or three hundred miles to a new hunting ground. It is not necessary to carry the house as it will be made from snow blocks wherever they decide to camp. Note the runners which are made of mud. The native term for mud is Noona which means land, 21
    - Verso: V-21; A typical Eskimo kommitik[?] with the entire household goods packed up ready to move two or three hundred miles to a new hunting ground. It is not necessary to carry the house as it will be made from snow blocks wherever they decide to camp. Note the runners which are made of mud. The native term for mud is Noona which means land, 21-verso
    - V-22; Niak-ko, one of the Aksiligsilingmuit. Niak-ko has a more pointed mustache and beard than is usual among the Eskimos who are usual clean of hair, there not being much hair on their faces, 22
    - Verso: V-22; Niak-ko, one of the Aksiligsilingmuit. Niak-ko has a more pointed mustache and beard than is usual among the Eskimos who are usual clean of hair, there not being much hair on their faces, 22-verso
    - V-23; A typical scene when building an igloo. The blocks are cut out from in inside, 23
    - Verso: V-23; A typical scene when building an igloo. The blocks are cut out from in inside, 23-verso
    - V-24; A white whale which is hunted in the same style as walrus, 24
    - Verso: V-24; A white whale which is hunted in the same style as walrus, 24-verso
    - V-25; A young Eskimo boy, 25
    - Verso: V-25; A young Eskimo boy, 25-verso
    - V-26; The same machine which is now at Baker Lake. This photo was taken near The Pas, Manitoba, on May 6, 1929, just after flying out from Churchill. The machine was run up on the shore ready to change to pontoons when the ice melted, 26
    - Verso: V-26; The same machine which is now at Baker Lake. This photo was taken near The Pas, Manitoba, on May 6, 1929, just after flying out from Churchill. The machine was run up on the shore ready to change to pontoons when the ice melted, 26-verso
    - V-27; Sirpapik who has been rather a belle in her own days, 27
    - Verso: V-27; Sirpapik who has been rather a belle in her own days, 27-verso
    - 28; A typical trading post, banked up for warmth. This snow is banked as protection against the wind, 28
    - Verso: 28; A typical trading post, banked up for warmth. This snow is banked as protection against the wind, 28-verso
    - V-29; Bob Stewart, one of the most picturesque of the northern traders, with part of the season's catch, 29
    - Verso: V-29; Bob Stewart, one of the most picturesque of the northern traders, with part of the season's catch, 29-verso
    - V-30; Typical Eskimo dogs. Photo taken at Eskimo Point, 30
    - Verso: V-30; Typical Eskimo dogs. Photo taken at Eskimo Point, 30-verso
    - V-31; A typical Eskimo igloo showing the man and wife standing in the entrance. A kommitik is on top of the igloo. These igloos, although it is difficult to build them, are strong enough to stand heavy weights. A few minutes after they are erected a man may walk on them, 31
    - Verso: V-31; A typical Eskimo igloo showing the man and wife standing in the entrance. A kommitik is on top of the igloo. These igloos, although it is difficult to build them, are strong enough to stand heavy weights. A few minutes after they are erected a man may walk on them, 31-verso
    - V-32; An igloo in the course of construction. The builder is inside cutting out snow blocks, 32
    - Verso: V-32; An igloo in the course of construction. The builder is inside cutting out snow blocks, 32-verso
    - V-33; Scene building an igloo. The blocks are fitted one into another. The igloo is built in circular fashion, gradually narrowing into the center, the last block being dropped in like a wedge, 33
    - Verso: V-33; Scene building an igloo. The blocks are fitted one into another. The igloo is built in circular fashion, gradually narrowing into the center, the last block being dropped in like a wedge, 33-verso
    - V-34; Another scene building an igloo. Instrument used is a long knife, 34
    - Verso: V-34; Another scene building an igloo. Instrument used is a long knife, 34-verso
  - Alaska: Vance photographs, 1929 - 1930; 6 (Box 1517)
    - V-35; Ak koolah, a fine old man who lives at Baker Lake, one of the Hanermuit tribe, 1
    - Verso: V-35; Ak koolah, a fine old man who lives at Baker Lake, one of the Hanermuit tribe, 1-verso
    - V-36 A typical husky dog, 2
    - Verso: V-36 A typical husky dog, 2-verso
    - V-37; Another view of a kommitik, 3
    - Verso: V-37; Another view of a kommitik, 3-verso
    - V-38; Nalik ti, which in English means "the one who listens." An excellent type of husky dog, grey in color, 4
    - Verso: V-38; Nalik ti, which in English means "the one who listens." An excellent type of husky dog, grey in color, 4-verso
    - V-39; A large igloo with a smaller one connecting, and a snow porch, 5
    - Verso: V-39; A large igloo with a smaller one connecting, and a snow porch, 5-verso
    - V-40; Isumataa Tingmashan which translated means the "boss of the airplane" Vance; C.N.R. Photo, Photographs Courtesy Canadian National Rys., 6
    - Verso: V-40; Isumataa Tingmashan which translated means the "boss of the airplane" Vance; C.N.R. Photo, Photographs Courtesy Canadian National Rys., 6-verso
    - V-41; This demonstrates the building of an igloo, 7
    - Verso: V-41; This demonstrates the building of an igloo, 7-verso
    - V-42; Siksik, a young Eskimo girl, 8
    - Verso: V-42; Siksik, a young Eskimo girl, 8-verso
    - V-43; Base of the Northern Aerial Minerals Exploration, Ltd., at Sioux Lookout, 9
    - Verso: V-43; Base of the Northern Aerial Minerals Exploration, Ltd., at Sioux Lookout, 9-verso
    - V-44; N.A.M.E. base at Sioux Lookout, Ont., 10
    - Verso: V-44; N.A.M.E. base at Sioux Lookout, Ont., 10-verso
    - V-45; Aerial view of Sioux Lookout [Ontario]. The busiest airplane base Abram Lake in foreground Pelican Lake in background., 11
    - Verso: V-45; Aerial view of Sioux Lookout [Ontario]. The busiest airplane base Abram Lake in foreground Pelican Lake in background., 11-verso
    - V-46; Waterfall in Northern Manitoba in country many miles from rail, 12
    - Verso: V-46; Waterfall in Northern Manitoba in country many miles from rail, 12-verso
    - V-47; My plane at Eskimo Point, April 1929. After a ten day's drift. Before the storm, the surface was level. The background is indistinct owing to the glare on the snow, and the low lying nature of the topography. The land being almost on the same level as the sea at this point, 13
    - Verso: V-47; My plane at Eskimo Point, April 1929. After a ten day's drift. Before the storm, the surface was level. The background is indistinct owing to the glare on the snow, and the low lying nature of the topography. The land being almost on the same level as the sea at this point, 13-verso
    - V-48; Dooley-a Padlermuit of Eskimo Point, 14
    - Verso: V-48; Dooley-a Padlermuit of Eskimo Point, 14-verso
    - V-49; Akpa, a Padlermuit. One of our guides. This man was most polite. His manners very courteous, somewhat like a Frenchman, 15
    - Verso: V-49; Akpa, a Padlermuit. One of our guides. This man was most polite. His manners very courteous, somewhat like a Frenchman, 15-verso
    - V-50; Two little girls at Eskimo Point. Note the igloo in rear. One little girl is wearing an artigi too large for her-her mother's, 16
    - Verso: V-50; Two little girls at Eskimo Point. Note the igloo in rear. One little girl is wearing an artigi too large for her-her mother's, 16-verso
    - V-51; Elooniuk - one of our guides - a mighty hunter and a fine man, 17
    - Verso: V-51; Elooniuk - one of our guides - a mighty hunter and a fine man, 17-verso
  - Vance photographs, 1929 - 1930; 7 (Box 1517)
    - [Man next to a totem pole in Alaska], 1
    - [Unidentified man next to a totem pole, Alaska], 2
    - [Man and dog in Alaska], 3
    - [Man playing with a dog in Alaska], 4
    - [Man, woman, and dog in Alaska], 5
    - [Dog jumping up on man in Alaska], 6
    - [Man and woman on bench next to totem pole, Alaska], 7
    - [Unidentified man standing in front of automobile], 8
    - [Man with hat standing in front of automobile], 9
    - [Man with hat standing in front of automobile], 10
    - [Man with hat standing in front of tree, Alaska (?)], 11